Guide to the Stanford University, Press, Archival Book Copies
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Press, archival book copies
1900-2013
SC4-9950
Stanford University. Press.
356 Linear feet (459 boxes)
The collection consists of archival copies of books published by Stanford University Press.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Collection is stored off-site; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical note
The Stanford University Press was established as an independent printing operation at Stanford University in 1892. The university purchased it in 1917, and expanded it into a full-service publishing house in 1925. In 1999, the Press became part of Stanford University Libraries and Academic Information Resources (SULAIR). It publishes scholarly monographs, textbooks, and professional reference works.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of archival copies of books published by Stanford University Press.
Arrangement note
Books in this collection are arranged by year of receipt by the Stanford University Archives (for post-1966 books, usually the year of publication).
Access Terms
Stanford University. Press.; University presses--California--Stanford.
Collection Contents
- Pre-1966
  - A Survey of Asian studies, prepared for the Ford Foundation., 1951
  - Best poems of ... Borestone Mountain poetry awards., 1949
  - Best poems of 1955: Borestone Mountain Poetry Awards 1956., 1957 (Box 73)
  - Borestone Mountain Poetry Awards., 1954 (Box 10)
  - Contributions to marine biology; lectures and symposia given at the Hopkins marine station, December 20-21, 1929, at the midwinter meeting of the Western society of naturalists., 1930
  - Dedication of the Hoover library on war, revolution, and peace, Stanford university, June 20, 1941.
  - Essays in memory of Morgan A. Gunst., 1962
  - Explanatory statement of the scope and purposes of the 1933 revision of the code of civil procedure.
  - Genetic studies of genius ..., 1925
  - George Edward Crothers, a Friend of the University., 1949 (Box 18)
  - In Memory of John Maxson Stillman., 1924 (Box 59)
  - Japan and America today; a symposium based on a conference on Japanese-American relations held at Honolulu under the auspices of the Institute of Pacific Relations of Hawaii., 1953
  - Logic, methodology, and philosophy of science; proceedings International Congress for Logic, Methodology, and Philosophy of Science (1st: 1960: Stanford, Calif.)., 1962
  - Mental disorders in later life., 1945
  - School case work manuals., 1943
  - Staged in arboreal beauty; being a description of Stanford University's woodland shrine ... Laurence Frost amphitheater., 1939
  - Stanford memorial church., 1946
  - Stanford short stories., 1946
  - The causes of the German collapse in 1918; sections of the officially1933., 1934
  - The Cubberley lectureship., 1938
  - The Hoover Institute and Library, Stanford Junior University is honored by the visit of His Excellency Celâl Bayar, President of the Republic of Turkey., 1954
  - The university and the future of America., 1941 (Box 10)
  - This fortunate man, Edward DeWitt Taylor, remarks upon the occasion of a dinner given in his honor., 1948 (Box 62)
  - Union list of serials of the San Francisco bay region, compiled by Special libraries association, San Francisco bay region chapter., 1939
  - Vocational guidance digest; a digest of material in current periodicals and in unbound form ..., 1935
  - Who's who in Latin America; a biographical dictionary of notable living men and women of Latin America., 1935
  - Abramovitz, Moses, et. al, The Allocation of economic resources; essays in honor of Bernard Francis Haley., 1959 (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Le Roy, 1874-1956, A new genus of the saxifrage family., 1929
  - Abrams, Le Roy, 1874-1956, Illustrated flora of the Pacific States: Washington, Oregon, and California; in 3 vols. Vol. 1., 1923 (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Le Roy, 1874-1956, Illustrated flora of the Pacific States: Washington, Oregon, and California; in 4vols. Vol. 1., 1940- (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Le Roy, 1874-1956, Illustrated flora of the Pacific States: Washington, Oregon, and California; in 4vols. Vol. 2 (2 cc)., 1940- (Box 2)
  - Abrams, Le Roy, 1874-1956, Illustrated flora of the Pacific States: Washington, Oregon, and California; in 4vols. Vol. 3-4., 1940- (Box 3)
  - Abrams, Le Roy, 1874-1956, Flora of Los Angeles and vicinity., 1904 (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Le Roy, 1874-1956, Flora of Los Angeles and vicinity., 1911 (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Le Roy, 1874-1956, Southern California Trees and Shrubs., 1910 (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, Robert William, 1910-, An index of the Arthurian names in Middle English., 1952
  - Adams, E. D, The Hoover War Collection at Stanford University California: a report and an analysis., 1921 (Box 73)
  - Adams, Ephraim Douglass, 1865-1930, The Hoover War Collection at Stanford Universty, California; a report and an analysis., 1921
  - Adams, Harlen Martin, 1904-, Speech guide for listeners and speakers., 1940
  - Adams, Harlen Martin, 1904-, The junior college library program; a study of library services in relation to instructional procedures., 1940
  - Adams, Virginia Best, 1904-, Illustrated guide to Yosemite Valley., 1952
  - Adelman, Irma, Theories of economic growth and development., 1965
  - Adelman, Irma, Theories of economic growth and development., 1964
  - Adelman, Irma, Theories of economic growth and development., 1962
  - Adler, John H. (John Hans), 1913-, Public finance and economic development in Guatemala., 1952 (Box 4)
  - Aiken, Howard, Switching Theory in Space Technology., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Albright, Horace M. (Horace Marden), 1890-1987, "Oh, ranger!" A book about the national parks., 1928
  - Allen, Herbert Francis, A study of the comedies of Richard Brome, especially as representative of dramatic decadence., 1912
  - Allen, Hollis Partridge, 1895-, Universal free education., 1934
  - Allen, Warren Dwight, Our marching civilization, an introduction to the study of music and society., 1943 (Box 4)
  - Aller, Paul, Build your own adobe., 1946 (Box 4)
  - Almond, Nina, The treaty of St. Germain; a documentary history..., 1935
  - Almond, Nina, An introduction to a bibliography of the Paris Peace Conference., 1935 (Box 4)
  - Alsberg, Carl, 1877-1940, Combination in the American bread-baking industry., 1926
  - Amo, Julián, La obra impresa de los intelectuales españoles en América, 1936-1945., 1950 (Box 4)
  - Anderson, H. Dewey, Ballots and the democratic class struggle; a study in the background of political education., 1943 (Box 4)
  - Anderson, H. Dewey, Recent occupational trends in American labor; a supplement... (2 cc)., 1945 (Box 5)
  - Anderson, H. Dewey (Hobson Dewey), 1897-, Alaska natives; a survey of their sociological and educational status., 1935
  - Anderson, H. Dewey (Hobson Dewey), 1897-, Occupational trends in the United States., 1940 (Box 4)
  - Anderson, H. Dewey (Hobson Dewey), 1897-, Our California state taxes; facts and problems., 1937
  - Anderson, Robert William, 1926-, Party politics in Puerto Rico., 1965 (Box 5)
  - Andrus, J. Russell, Burmese economic life., 1947
  - Andrus, J. Russell (James Russell), 1902-, The economy of Pakistan., 1958 (Box 5)
  - Annand, Percy Nicol, 1898-, A contribution toward a monograph of the Adelginae (Phylloxeridae) of North America., 1928
  - Anrep, Gleb Vasilevich, 1891-, Lane medical lectures: Studies in cardiovascular regulation., 1936
  - Anthony, Joseph Garner, Hawaii under Army rule., 1955 (Box 5)
  - Appel, Alfred, James Joyce; an appreciation., 1964
  - Arms, George Warren, 1912-, The fields were green; a new view of Bryant, Whittier, Holmes, Lowell, and Longfellow, with a selection of their poems., 1953 (Box 5)
  - Arnstein, Flora J, Adventures into poetry., 1951 (Box 5)
  - Arrow, Kenneth Joseph, 1921-, Mathematical Methods in the Social Sciences, 1959., 1960 (Box 5)
  - Arrow, Kenneth Joseph, 1921-, Studies in applied probability and management science., 1962
  - Arrow, Kenneth Joseph, 1921-, Studies in linear and non-linear programming., 1958
  - Arrow, Kenneth Joseph, 1921-, Studies in the mathematical theory of inventory and production., 1958 (Box 5)
  - Astronomical Society of the Pacific, The Adolfo Stahl lectures in astronomy, delivered in San Francisco, California, in 1916-17 and 1917-18., 1919
  - Baas-Becking, Lourens Gerhard Marinus, 1895-, Studies on growth: part I. The point binomial and its derivatives., 1926
  - Bailey, Thomas Andrew, 1902-, Theodore Roosevelt and the Japanese-American crises; an account of the international complications arising from the race problem on the Pacific Coast., 1934
  - Ball, M. Margaret, The problem of inter-American organization., 1944
  - Ball, M. Margaret (Mary Margaret), 1909-, Post-war German-Austrian relations; the anschluss movement, 1918-1936., 1937
  - Ballantine, Joseph, Japanese as it is spoken; a beginner's grammar., 1945 (Box 6)
  - Ballantine, Joseph, b. 1888, Japanese as it is spoken: a beginner's grammar., 1950 (Box 6)
  - Banani, Amin, The modernization of Iran, 1921-1941., 1961 (Box 6)
  - Bane, Suda Lorena, Organization of American relief in Europe, 1918-1919., 1943 (Box 6)
  - Bane, Suda Lorena, 1886-, The blockade of Germany after the armistice, 1918-1919;., 1942
  - Barahal, George D, Converting a veterans guidance center., 1950
  - Barber, William J, The economy of British Central Africa; a case study of economic development in a dualistic society., 1961 (Box 6)
  - Bark, William Carroll, 1908-, Origins of the medieval world., 1958 (Box 6)
  - Barker, Roger G, Big school, small school; high school size and student behavior., 1964 (Box 6)
  - Barnes, Donald Grove, George III and William Pitt, 1783-1806. A new interpretation based upon a study of their unpublished correspondence., 1939
  - Baron, Samuel H, Plekhanov; the father of Russian Marxism., 1963 (Box 6)
  - Barry, E. Eldon, Nationalisation in British Politics., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Bartky, A. John, 1899-, Administration as educational leadership., 1956 (Box 7)
  - Bateson, Gregory, Naven: a survey of the problems suggested by a composite picture of the culture of a New Guinea tribe drawn from three points of view., 1958 (Box 7)
  - Bay, Christian, 1921-, The structure of freedom., 1958 (Box 7)
  - Beach, Walter Greenwood, 1868-1948, American social problems., 1934 (Box 7)
  - Beach, Walter Greenwood, 1868-1948, Oriental crime in California; a study of offenses committed by Orientals in that state, 1900-1927., 1932
  - Beach, Walter Greenwood, 1868-1948, Social aims in a changing world., 1932 (Box 7)
  - Beaumont, Gustave de, 1802-1866, Marie; or, Slavery in the United States: a novel of Jacksonian America., 1958 (Box 7)
  - Becker, Carl Lotus, 1873-1945, Progress and power; three lectures delivered at Stanford University., 1936 (Box 7)
  - Beckwith, Burnham D, The Economic Theory of a Socialist Economy., 1949 (Box 7)
  - Beebe, Lucius Morris, 1902-1966, Comstock commotion; the story of the Territorial enterprise and Virginia City news., 1954 (Box 7)
  - Beebe, Lucius Morris, 1902-1966, Legends of the Comstock Lode., 1954
  - Beebe, Lucius Morris, 1902-1966, Virginia & Truckee; a story of Virginia City and Comstock times., 1955
  - Bell, Hugh M, The theory and practice of personal counseling, with special reference to the Adjustment inventory., 1935
  - Bell, Reginald, 1894-, Public school education of second-generation Japanese in California., 1935
  - Bemis, Maynard, Boardsmanship; a guide for the school board member.., 1955 (Box 8)
  - Bemis, Maynard, Boardsmanship; a guide for the school board member.., 1961 (Box 8)
  - Benjamin, Harold Raymond Wayne, 1893-1969, Emergent conceptions of the school administrator's task,., 1942
  - Bennett, Merrill Kelley, Farm Cost Stuides in the United States., 1928 (Box 8)
  - Bennett, Merrill Kelley, International commodity stockpiling as an economic stabilizer, by M. K. Bennett and associates., 1949
  - Benson, Gilbert Thereon, 1896-1928, The trees and shrubs of western Oregon., 1930 (Box 8)
  - Benson, Ivan, b. 1896, Mark Twain's western years., 1938 (Box 8)
  - Berkes, Ross N, The diplomacy of India; Indian foreign policy in the United Nations., 1958 (Box 8)
  - Berner, Bertha, Mrs. Leland Stanford; an intimate account., 1935
  - Bershader, Daniel, Plasma Hydromagnetics., 1962 (Box 8)
  - Bershader, Daniel, The Magnetodynamics of Conducting Fluids., 1959 (Box 8)
  - Bestor, Arthur Eugene, David Jacks of Monterey, and Lee L. Jacks, his daughter., 1945 (Box 1)
  - Bibler, Richard N, Little Man on Campus., 1952 (Box 8)
  - Biegal, Bernard et. al., eds, Biennial Review of Anthropology: 1961, 1963, 1965, 1967, 1969, 1971. (Box 9)
  - Billig, Harvey E, Mobilization of the human body: newer concepts in body mechanics., 1949
  - Binder, Raymond C., ed, Proceedings of the 1961 heat transfer and fluid mechanics institute. (Box 8)
  - Bingham, Joseph Walter, 1878-1973, Report on the international law of Pacific coastal fisheries., 1938 (Box 8)
  - Birnbach, Martin, Neo-Freudian social philosophy., 1961 (Box 8)
  - Blagden, Cyprian, The stationers' company: a history, 1403-1959., 1960
  - Blasdale, Walter Charles, b. 1871, Cyclamen persicum; its natural and cultivated forms., 1952
  - Blenner-Hassett, Roland, A study of the place-names in Lawman's Brut., 1950
  - Blum, Richard H, Health and healing in rural Greece; a study of three communities., 1965 (Box 8)
  - Boeninger, Hildegard R, The Hoover Library collection on Germany., 1955
  - Bonner, Willard Hallam, 1899-, Captain William Dampier, buccaneer-author., 1934
  - Booth, Ernest S, Birds of the West; illustrated by Harry Baerg and Carl Petterson., 1950 (Box 9)
  - Booth, George C, Mexico's school-made society., 1941
  - Boswell, James, 1740-1795, The hypochondriack, being the seventy essays by the celebrated biographer, James Boswell.. .. V1-2 (2 cc)., 1928 (Box 10)
  - Bourret, F. M, Ghana, the road to independence, 1919-1957., 1960 (Box 10)
  - Bourret, F. M, The Gold Coast: a survey of the Gold Coast and British Togoland, 1919-1951., 1952
  - Bourret, F. M, The Gold Coast; a survey of the Gold Coast and British Togoland, 1919-1946., 1949
  - Bozeman, Adda B, Regional conflicts around Geneva; an inquiry into the origin, nature, and implications of the neutralized zone of Savoy and of the customs-free zones of Gex and Upper Savoy.., 1949
  - Bracewell, Ronald, ed, Paris Symposium on Radio Astronomy., 1959 (Box 11)
  - Bradley, Harold Whitman, The American frontier in Hawaii; the pioneers, 1789-1843, by Harold Whitman Bradley., 1942 (Box 11)
  - Brailsford, Henry Noel, The Levellers and the English revolution 1873-1958.., 1961 (Box 11)
  - Brand, Carl Fremont, British labour's rise to power; eight studies., 1941
  - Brand, Carl Fremont, The British Labour Party, a short history., 1964 (Box 11)
  - Brandt, Karl, 1899-, Management of agriculture and food in the German-occupied and other areas of fortress Europe: a study in military government., 1953
  - Brant, Sebastian, 1458-1521, Descensus Averno; fourteen woodcuts reproduced from Sebastian Brant's Virgil, Strassburg, MDII., 1930
  - Brasch, Frederick E, Sir Isaac Newton; an essay on Sir Isaac Newton and Newtonian thought as exemplified in the Stanford collection of books, manuscripts, and prints concerning celestial mechanics, optics, mathematics, and related disciplines as a history of natural philosophy., 1962
  - Breshko-Breshkovskaia, Ekaterina Konstantinovna,, Hidden springs of the Russian revolution: personal memoirs of Katerina Breshkovskaia., 1931
  - Bretton, Henry L., 1916-, Stresemann and the revision of Versailles; a fight for reason., 1953 (Box 11)
  - Briggs, Mitchell Pirie, George D. Herron and the European settlement., 1932
  - Brim, Orville Gilbert, 1923-, Personality and decision processes; studies in the social psychology of thinking., 1962
  - Brinton, Anna Cox, Maphaeus Vegius and his Thirteenth Book of the Aeneid., 1930 (Box 11)
  - Britnell, George E, Canadian agriculture in war and peace, 1935-50., 1962 (Box 11)
  - Broderick, Francis L, W. E. B. Du Bois, Negro leader in a time of crisis., 1959 (Box 12)
  - Brooks, Juanita, The Mountain Meadows Massacre., 1950
  - Brose, Olive J., Church and Parliament; the reshaping of the Church of England, 1828-1860., 1959 (Box 12)
  - Browder, Robert Paul, The Russian Provisional Government, 1917: documents., 1961
  - Brower, Robert H, Japanese court poetry., 1961 (Box 12)
  - Brown, Vinson, 1912-, It all happened right here!: a child's history of Santa Clara County., 1954
  - Bruntz, George G, Allied propaganda and the collapse of the German empire in 1918., 1938
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, ed, Africa and the Communist World., 1963 (Box 12)
  - Buell, Robert Kingery, California stepping-stones., 1948 (Box 12)
  - Buell, Robert Kingery, Verse writing simplified., 1940
  - Bullough, Edward, 1880-1934, Æsthetics: lectures and essays., 1957 (Box 12)
  - Bunyan, James, 1898-, The Bolshevik revolution, 1917-1918; documents and materials., 1934
  - Burks, Barbara Stoddard, 1902-1943, The promise of youth: follow-up studies of a thousand gifted children., 1930
  - Burns, Edward McNall, 1897-, David Starr Jordan: prophet of freedom., 1953 (Box 12)
  - Burton, Robert, 1577-1640, Robert Burton's Philosophaster, with an English translation of the same.., 1931
  - Bush, Robert R, Studies in mathematical learning theory., 1959
  - Butler, Samuel, 1835-1902, The family letters of Samuel Butler, 1841-1886., 1962 (Box 12)
  - Butow, Robert J. C. (Robert Joseph Charles), 1924-, Japan's decision to surrender., 1954 (Box 12)
  - Buttle, Myra, 1896-1965, Malaya: communist or free?., 1954
  - Butwell, Richard A, U Nu of Burma., 1963 (Box 13)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Health Yearbook., 1953 (Box 13)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Health Yearbook., 1954 (Box 14)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Health Yearbook., 1955 (Box 14)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Health Yearbook., 1956 (Box 14)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Health Instruction Yearbook., 1943 (Box 13)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Health Instruction Yearbook., 1944 (Box 13)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Health Instruction Yearbook., 1951 (Box 13)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Nutrition sourcebook., 1955 (Box 13)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, School health sourcebook., 1955 (Box 13)
  - Byrd, Oliver Erasmus, Family life sourcebook., 1956 (Box 13)
  - Byrne, Charles David, 1895-, Co-ordinated control of higher education in Oregon., 1940
  - California Council on Improvement of Instruction, Better learning through current materials., 1952
  - California Library Association, California local history; a centennial bibliography., 1950
  - California School Boards Association. Boardsmanship Revision Committee, Boardsmanship; a guide for the school board member., 1960
  - California. Dept. of Education, Physical education; a wartime and peacetime program for girls., 1943
  - Callcott, Wilfrid Hardy, 1895-, Liberalism in Mexico, 1857-1929., 1931
  - Cameron, Meribeth Elliott, 1905-, The reform movement in China, 1898-1912., 1931
  - Campbell, Douglas Houghton, 1859-1953, The evolution of the land plants Embryophyta., 1940
  - Cancian, Frank, Economics and prestige in a Maya community; the religious cargo system in Zinacantán., 1965 (Box 14)
  - Carr, William George, 1901-, Education for war and peace., 1942 (Box 14)
  - Carr, William George, 1901-, Education for world-citizenship., 1928 (Box 14)
  - Carr, William George, 1901-, Educational leadership in this emergency, 1942.
  - Carr, William George, 1901-, School finance., 1933 (Box 14)
  - Carr, William George, 1901-, The lesson assignment., 1931
  - Carswell, John, The South Sea bubble., 1960
  - Carter, Harold Dean, Vocational interests and job orientation, a ten-year review., 1944
  - Case, Roscoe David, The platoon school in America., 1931
  - Ch'ên, Jerome, 1919-, Yuan Shih-k'ai, 1859-1916; Brutus assumes the purple., 1961 (Box 15)
  - Chadwick, Owen, The mind of the Oxford movement., 1960 (Box 14)
  - Chalfant, W. A, Gold, guns & ghost towns., 1947
  - Chalfant, W. A. (Willie Arthur), 1868-1943, Death Valley: the facts., 1936
  - Chalfant, W. A. (Willie Arthur), 1868-1943, Death Valley; the facts., 1930
  - Chamberlin, Waldo, 1905-, Industrial relations in Germany, 1914-1939; annotated bibliography., 1942 (Box 14)
  - Chamberlin, Waldo, 1905-, Industrial relations in wartime: Great Britain, 1914-1918., 1940 (Box 14)
  - Chan, Shau Wing, Elementary Chinese., 1951 (Box 15)
  - Chan, Shau Wing, A concise English-Chinese dictionary, with romanized standard pronunciation., 1955
  - Chan, Shau Wing, A concise English-chinese dictionary; with romanized standard pronunication., 1946 (Box 15)
  - Chan, Shau Wing, Supplementary vocabulary for "Chinese Reader for Beginners"., 1943
  - Chateaubriand, Francois-Rene, vicomte de, 1768-1848, Atala; or, The love and constancy of two savages in the desert., 1930 (Box 15)
  - Child, Stephen, Landscape architecture, a series of letters., 1927
  - Chittenden, Hiram Martin, 1858-1917, Yellowstone national park, historical & descriptive., 1933
  - Chittenden, Hiram Martin, 1858-1917, Yellowstone national park, historical & descriptive; 2nd ed., 1949 (Box 15)
  - Chow Tse-tsung, The May Fourth Movement [1967 paperback]., 1960 (Box 15)
  - Christ, Carl F., et. al, Measurement in economics; studies in mathematical economics and econometrics in memory of Yehuda Grunfeld., 1963 (Box 16)
  - Claremont (Calif.). Social Research Center, California local finance., 1960 (Box 16)
  - Clark, Arthur Bridgman, 1866-1948, Significant paintings at the Panama-Pacific Exhibition: how to find them and how to enjoy them., 1915
  - Clark, Arthur Bridgman, 1866-1948, Art principles in house, furniture, and village building; an exposition of designing principles which every house builder, furniture user, and village dweller should know., 1921
  - Clark, Arthur Bridgman, 1866-1948, Perspective; a textbook and manual for artists, architects and students., 1936 (Box 16)
  - Clark, George Thomas, 1862-1940, Leland Stanford, war governor of California, railroad builder and founder of Stanford university., 1931
  - Clark, Lew, 1904-, Pocket guide to the south boundary country / Yosemite National Park., 1955
  - Clark, Lew, 1904-, Trail guide to the High Sierra camp areas of Yosemite National Park., 1953
  - Clark, Lew, 1904-, Trail guide to the north country / Yosemite National Park., 1954 (Box 16)
  - Clarke, James Mitchell, Public school camping; California's pilot project in outdoor education., 1951
  - Clavigero, Francesco Saverio, 1731-1787, The history of Lower California., 1937
  - Clokie, Hugh McDowall, 1900-, Royal commissions of inquiry; the significance of investigations in British politics., 1937 (Box 16)
  - Cloud, Roy W, Education in California., 1952 (Box 16)
  - Coan, Otis Weldon, America in fiction; an annotated list of novels that interpret aspects of life in the United States., 1941 (Box 16)
  - Coan, Otis Welton, America in fiction, an annotated list of novels that interpret aspects of life in the United States., 1945 (Box 16)
  - Coladarci, Arthur P, The use of theory in educational administration., 1955
  - Cole, Margaret, 1893-1980, The story of Fabian socialism., 1961 (Box 16)
  - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1772-1834, Confessions of an inquiring spirit., 1957 (Box 16)
  - Collins, Carvel, ed, Sam Ward in the Gold Rush., 1949 (Box 17)
  - Collins, Ivan L, Horse power days; popular vehicles of nineteenth century America., 1953 (Box 16)
  - Colombat, Francis Henry, A commonwealth of nations., 1943